

Chetan Philips

Sales & Customer Service Professional

E-Mail: chetan.philips@gmail.com; chetan.philips@hotmail.com

Mobile: +91 9909887474 and +919099773399

Synopsis

I am a Customer Service & Sales professional with 20+ years of experience in the field of managing contact centers – Sales, Customer Service, Collections, Voice, Non- Voice, Inbound, Outbound, Captive, and Outsourced – and Sales & Customer Service Operation in field operations, Service Project Management and Back Office Service Operations managing small and large teams across multiple locations.

My track record demonstrates self- motivation and initiative to achieve both personal and corporate goals and thus reached higher echelons of career through promotions by way of thoroughly professional attitude.

Professional Attributes

- Customer focused and ability to respond to their needs
- Excellent people management skills
- Driving SLAs for multiple processes
- Ability to drive sales through building relationships with potential customers
- Service Partner Management
- Excellent written and spoken communication skills
- Counseling and training
- Maintain understanding of client specific training needs
- Adept in mapping customer requirements and implementing strategies to achieve client satisfaction, tracking market dynamics and initiating reinforcements
- Farsighted with global vision

Skills

LEADERSHIP

- Promoting a culture of informed decision making ensuring that units of corporate responsibility is planned, structured and focused
- Ability to guide individuals towards goal achievement by teamwork, motivation and being a role model within the organization
- Mentoring, motivating and coaching talent to achieve the set objectives
- Providing effective and inspirational leadership to the team through regular training, motivation and suitable incentives in order to achieve set targets

STRATEGIC PLANNING

Formulating developmental strategies for achievement of goals and targets by identifying and developing new avenues for long term growth

PROJECT MANAGEMENT

Managing activities right from the conceptualization stage to the execution; involving

finalization of technical specifications

- Managing and implementing contact center strategy and delivery
- Establishing project review, monitoring and status reporting procedures to accurately report progress of the project to the user clients
- Handling activities involving working out various requirements and monitoring overall project operations for ensuring timely completion with adherence to quality guided by specification.

Experience

P4 CALLNET SERVICES LLP, BARODA, GUJARAT 04/2021—Ongoing Partner (Entrepreneur)

Began journey of entrepreneurship in the BPO space.

FIVE SPLASH INFOTECH, HUBLI, KARNATAKA 05/2018-11/2019 Center Head (Sr. Manager)

- To monitor the customer defined KPIs for all LOBs at the center Resource and capacity planning across the delivery team.
- To monitor the support functions at the center as per the requirement of the operations teams
 - Effectively manage risks, issues and process deviations
- Ensuring operational strategies are implemented
- Monitoring and ensuring revenue streams
- Ensuring billable hours as per revenue forecasts
- Monitoring HR, Admin & IT functions for key deliverables towards end user satisfaction Span of Control: Dept. Heads for HR, Admin, IT, Q&T & Operations: 550 people Client Projects: customer service, telesales, order fulfillment, non-voice data replication.

Consultant: On-boarded a premium client (Operations, Finance, Tele-sales & Collections) for Fivesplash Infotech at one of their centers, from Sept. '19 – Nov. '19.

FREELANCE TRAINER, GUJARAT

8/2012-Ongoing

Freelance Trainer

- Conducted corporate trainings on behalf of other training organizations like Centum Learning, ACTUNIV etc.
- Trained on selling skills, soft skills, communication skills, personality development, foreign trade management, customer service skills.

JHP EDU FOUNDATION, RAJKOT, GUJARAT

4/2014-4/2018

Head – Call Center & Telecommunications

- Setup and managed hybrid call center inbound/outbound, voice/non-voice
- Managed the telecommunication infrastructure

Manager, Customer Service

o Prepaid Call Center Head

Span of Control – 1000 agents, 50 team coaches, 25 team leaders, 4 team operations-in-charges; Duration - 2 years

Sales & CS Head – Ahmedabad

Span of Control – 13 Vodafone Stores, 1 Mobile store, 28 Vodafone Mini Stores; Duration - 1.5 years

Outbound Calling

Span of Control–300 agents,10 team leaders, 3teamoperations- in-charges; Duration - 1.5 years

Outbound Calling National Team (Corporate Delegation)

Rolled out Genesys Outbound Dialer across all Vodafone India

Circles; Duration - 1.5 years

Back Office CS Operations; Duration - 0.5 years

Name of Company	Location	Position Held	From	То
CARPHONE WAREHOUSE PLC	London, UK	Credit Control & Collections Advisor	01/2004	03/2005
TATA TELECOM	Ahmedabad, Gujarat	Asst. Manager, Back Office	05/2003	09/2003
BHARTI AIRTEL	Ahmedabad, Gujarat	Sr. Executive – Customer Service	02/2002	04/2003
BG BROADBAND	Surat, Gujarat	Sr. Executive – Call Center	10/2001	02/2002
BIRLA AT&T COMM. LTD. (Now Idea Cellular Limited)	Gandhinagar, Gujarat	Executive – Call Center	10/1998	10/2001

Education

Name of Institute	Course Undertaken	From	То
Northumbria University, London School of Commerce	Masters In International Business Administration	10/2003	05/2005
Ahmedabad Management Association	Post Graduate Diploma in Human Resource Management	07/1999	05/2000
St. Xavier's College, Ahmedabad	Bachelor of Arts (English Literature)	06/1995	04/1998

Personal Details DATE OF BIRTH: 08 AUGUST 1974

LANGUAGES: ENGLISH, HINDI & GUJARATI